John Gibler Papers, 1890-2006
University of Minnesota Libraries
- Crop-Related Publications
  - Oversized charts of wheat crosses and an organizational chart of the Argentine agricultural ministry, 1980. (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Publications by John Gibler, undated, 1949, 1953, 1956, 1963. (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Note cards on wheat crosses, undated. (Box 4, Folder 25)
    120 Note cards.
  - Bibliography, 1975. (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous wheat-related articles and reports, 1978-1982. (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Wheat pedigrees, undated. (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Wheat Crosses, Mexico and South America, undated, 1947-1959. (Box 5, Folder 10)
    Includes letter from Gibler to Norman Borlaug.
  - Wheat crosses and pedigrees, 1960-1971. (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - “Cultivares de Trigo Lancadas no Rio Grande de Sul a Partir de 1979.” (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous wheat crossing-related materials, 1965-1975. (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - “Grain Qualities of the Krasnodar Wheat Variety” in New Varieties of Winter Wheat: Prutskova, M.G. and Ukhanova, I.O. Kolos Press: Moscow, 1972. (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Wheat Abbreviations, CIMMYT, 1978-1979. (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Two publications on cereals in Kenya, 1958. (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - “Trials: South American Wheat Introductions 1963/64.” Atsmon, Y. Hazera Seed Growing Cie. Research Department, Mivhor Farm, Israel, 1964. (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Wheat varieties by country, A-Z, undated. (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - USDA. “Rust Reaction of new Introductions and Spring Habit Common Wheats from the World Collection Grown in Mexico in the Summer of 1952.” Borlaug, NE, Gibler, JW, Narveaz, I, et al, 1953. (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - USDA. “World Collection of Wheat. Data Compilation #2: Disease and Agronomic Data Recorded on Strains of Wheat Species Collection grown at Chapingo and Trapunto, Mexico in 1952; St Croix, Virgin Islands and Mayaguez, Puerto Rico in 1952-1953 and St. Paul Minnesota in 1954” Ward, D.J. Beltsville, MD, 1956. (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - USDA. “Rust Reaction to Durum Wheats from the World Collection Grown in Mexico, Summer of 1952” Borlaug, NE, Gibler, JW, Campos, A. et al; Beltsville, MD, 1953. (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - USDA. “Reaction of 105 Selected Wheat Varieties in the 1957 International Seedling Test Nursery to Individual Races of Stem and Leaf Rust,” Beltsville, MD, 1958. (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - “Reactions of Wheats From World Collection to Stem Rust 1952” (Box 5, Folder 23)
    2 copies.
  - Wheat pedigrees, 1969-1970. (Box 5, Folder 28)
    “Colecao de Cultivares De Trigo” (Portuguese); “Variedades de Trigo para la Costa Central del Peru” (Spanish) and “Informatcao Sobre O Comportamento em Relacao a P. graminis tritici da veridades em Cultivo e Linhagens, no Palnio de Verao de 1969/1970” (Portuguese).
- Awards and Honoraria
  - New York Academy of Sciences certification, 1973. (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - American Phytopathological Society Membership Emeritus certification. (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Certificate of Honor, City of Cruz Alta, Rio Grande Do Sul, Brasil. (Box 6)
  - Plaques, medals, and miscellaneous, 1950s-2000s. (Box 6)
    Includes E.C. Stakman award.
- Miscellaneous
  - Photographs, circa 1960s-1970s. (Box 1, Folder 1-4)
    Include photographs of E.C. Stakman and Norman Borlaug.
  - Snapshot albums of South American plantations activities, circa 1960s. (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1950s-1990s. (Box 1, Folder 7-15)
    Clipping from English and Spanish language newspapers.
  - Spanish language newspaper clippings. (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - South American travel notebook, circa 1960s. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Clippings and speeches by/about Norman Borlaug, circa 1970s. (Box 1, Folder 17-18)
  - Background information on CIMMYT, 1980s. (Box 1, Folder 19-22)
  - Biographical information, circa 1946-2006. (Box 1, Folder 23)